<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Swapi Express</string>

    <string-array name="data_title">
        <item>Godzilla (star)</item>
        <item>V4650 Sagittarii (qF362)</item>
        <item>NGC 2363-V1</item>
        <item>M33-013406.63</item>
        <item>Eta Carinae</item>
        <item>V4998 Sagittarii</item>
        <item>R136c</item>
        <item>Arches Cluster</item>
        <item>V1429 Aquilae</item>
        <item>R136a3</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="data_secondary">
        <item>Godzilla is a variable star in the Sunburst galaxy at redshift z = 2.38 (or 10.9 billion light years from Earth), observed through the gravitational lens PSZ1 G311.65-18.48.[1] It was originally identified as a possible transient event in images taken with the Hubble Space Telescope (HST).[2] As of October 2022, it is the most luminous star that can be currently observed.[1][3] This is possible thanks to the fact that the star is believed to be undergoing an episode of temporary increased luminosity that has lasted at least seven years, combined with an estimated magnification of at least a factor of 2000. Some spectral features in Godzilla resemble those of other variable stars in the Milky Way Galaxy such as Eta Carinae suggesting that Godzilla could be close to the end of its life. Godzilla is believed to be going through an episode similar to the Great Eruption of Eta Carinae in the 19th century, during which the star was likely among the brightest in the universe at about 50 million L☉. </item>
        <item>V4650 Sgr was first catalogued in 1996 as star 362 in a list of stars in the galactic centre region near the Quintuplet Cluster.[5] The acronym qF is used for stars in the list and so the star name is qF 362. The acronym FMM is also used, hence FMM 362.[6] The LBV nature of qF 362 was not recognised until 1999.[7] It is one of three LBVs close to the Quintuplet Cluster, all highly luminous stars.[8]</item>
        <item>NGC 2363-V1 is a luminous blue variable star in the star-forming region NGC 2363, at the far southwestern part of the irregular galaxy NGC 2366 in the constellation Camelopardalis, near the north celestial pole nearly 11 million light years away from our galaxy. It was discovered in 1996 by Laurent Drissen, Jean-René Roy, and Carmelle Robert while examining images taken by the Hubble Space Telescope Wide Field Planetary Camera 2.[1] </item>
        <item>M33-013406.63, also known as B416,[4] is a blue supergiant star in the constellation of Triangulum. It is located within the Triangulum Galaxy, which is approximately 2,380,000–3,070,000 light years away from Earth. </item>
        <item>Eta Carinae (η Carinae, abbreviated to η Car), formerly known as Eta Argus, is a stellar system containing at least two stars with a combined luminosity greater than five million times that of the Sun, located around 7,500 light-years (2,300 parsecs) distant in the constellation Carina. Previously a 4th-magnitude star, it brightened in 1837 to become brighter than Rigel, marking the start of its so-called "Great Eruption". It became the second-brightest star in the sky between 11 and 14 March 1843 before fading well below naked-eye visibility after 1856. In a smaller eruption, it reached 6th magnitude in 1892 before fading again. It has brightened consistently since about 1940, becoming brighter than magnitude 4.5 by 2014. </item>
        <item>V4998 Sagittarii is a luminous blue variable star (LBV) in the constellation of Sagittarius. Located some 25,000 light-years away, the star is positioned about 7 pc (23 ly) away from a starburst cluster known as the Quintuplet cluster. It has an ejection nebula measuring over 0.8 pc in diameter, formed 5000-10,000 years ago through large eruptions. The star has a large mass comparable to the Pistol Star and a luminosity of around 4 million times the Sun (L☉). This places the star as one of the most massive and luminous stars known. </item>
        <item>R136c is a star located in R136, a tight knot of stars at the centre of NGC 2070, an open cluster weighing 450,000 solar masses and containing 10,000 stars.[5] At 142 M☉ and 3.8 million L☉, it is the one of the most massive stars known and one of the most luminous, along with being one of the hottest, at over 40,000 K. It was first resolved and named by Feitzinger in 1980, along with R136a and R136b.[6] </item>
        <item>The Arches Cluster is the densest known star cluster in the Milky Way, about 100 light-years from its center in the constellation Sagittarius (The Archer), 25,000 light-years from Earth. Its discovery was reported by Nagata et al. in 1995,[1] and independently by Cotera et al. in 1996.[2] Due to extremely heavy optical extinction by dust in this region, the cluster is obscured in the visual bands, and is observed in the X-ray, infrared and radio bands. It contains approximately 135 young, very hot stars that are many times larger and more massive than the Sun, plus many thousands of less massive stars.[3]</item>
        <item>V1429 Aquilae is a candidate luminous blue variable multiple star system located in the constellation of Aquila. It is often referred to by its Mount Wilson Observatory catalog number as MWC 314. It is a hot luminous star with strong emission lines in its spectrum. </item>
        <item>R136a3 is a Wolf–Rayet star in R136, a massive star cluster located in Dorado. It is located near R136a1, the most massive and luminous star known. R136a3 is itself one of the most massive and most luminous stars known at about 179 times more massive and 5 million times more luminous than the Sun.
The formal name of the star is RMC 136a3, standing for Radcliffe observatory, Magellanic Clouds, 136a3. The RMC survey identified luminous objects in the Large Magellanic Cloud and one of the brightest was RMC 136. This is now commonly shortened to R136, which is now known to be an extremely young dense open cluster at the core of the NGC 2070 cluster in the Tarantula Nebula. R136 was eventually resolved and the brightest "star" at the centre was termed R136a. This was further resolved into multiple components, one of which is R136a3. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="data_support">
        <item>The extreme magnification of Godzilla is partially due to a nearby substructure, probably a dwarf galaxy, not seen in the HST images, that is also close to the critical curve of the cluster. This unobserved substructure is believed to be dominated by dark matter.[1]</item>
        <item>V4650 was discovered using infrared telescopes. It is extremely faint at optical wavelengths due to interstellar extinction. The 2MASS survey recorded it at 17th magnitude in red light and 19th magnitude in blue light, while it is a 7th magnitude object in K band infrared.[1]</item>
        <item>NGC 2363-V1 is one of the most luminous stars known. It has been undergoing an increase in temperature and luminosity for the last 20 years, after a dramatic increase in its rate of mass loss. Significant luminosity variation within a human lifetime is rare in LBVs, e.g. Eta Carinae during its Great Eruption (1837 to 1855). NGC 2363-V1 shows an extreme B hypergiant spectrum similar to P Cygni rather than the presently cool Eta Carinae outburst spectrum.[1][2]</item>
        <item>It is potentially one of the most luminous stars ever discovered, estimated to be approximately between 3 and 10 million times more luminous than the Sun, although it is thought likely to be a multiple star system.[3] Modelling of the spectrum based on some assumptions about the relative sizes of the two stars suggests a secondary around half a million times as luminous as the Sun and the primary over four million times as luminous as the Sun.[2]</item>
        <item>Although unrelated to the star and nebula, the weak Eta Carinids meteor shower has a radiant very close to Eta Carinae. </item>
        <item>The star\'s high mass loss rate combined with its eruptions will strip off its hydrogen layers and expose a hot helium core. It will proceed to the Wolf–Rayet sequence. It will eventually start fusing heavy elements in its core, and when it develops a large iron core the star will collapse in on itself and explode as a type Ib or Ic supernovae. Depending on the amount of mass lost before the supernova explosion, the remnant will be a neutron star or black hole. A black hole is predicted for the most massive stars such as this one.[10]</item>
        <item>Its fate depends on the amount of mass it loses before its core collapses, but is likely to result in a supernova. The most recent models for single star evolution at near-solar metallicities suggest that the most massive stars explode as highly stripped type Ic supernovae, although different outcomes are possible for binaries. Some of these supernovae are expected to produce a type of gamma-ray burst and the expected remnant is a black hole.[9]</item>
        <item>The star cluster is estimated to be around two and a half million years old.[3][4] Although larger and denser than the nearby Quintuplet Cluster, it appears to be slightly younger. Only stars earlier and more massive than O5 have evolved away from the main sequence while the Quintuplet Cluster includes a number of hot supergiants as well as a red supergiant and three luminous blue variables.[4]</item>
        <item>In infrared spectra, the Pfund series of lines are strongly in emission, a very unusual feature characteristic of supergiant Be stars and LBVs. V1429 Aql is given a B2:e spectral type from analysis in the infrared.[9]</item>
        <item>Although R136a3 has a Wolf-Rayet spectral type dominated by intense emission lines of helium and nitrogen, usually indicating a highly evolved star that has lost its outer layers, R136a3 is actually an extremely young star. The spectrum also includes hydrogen lines and analysis shows the star is still 40% hydrogen at the surface. The helium and nitrogen in the atmosphere of such a young star are caused by strong convection due to the massive core and intense CNO cycle fusion, enhanced further by rotational mixing. The emission lines in the spectrum indicate strong mass loss caused by the fusion products at the surface and the enormous luminosity.[2][7]</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="data_image">
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/08/The_Sunburst_Arc_PSZ1_G311.65-18.48.jpg/3000px-The_Sunburst_Arc_PSZ1_G311.65-18.48.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6a/Uncovering_the_secrets_of_the_Quintuplet_Cluster.jpg/280px-Uncovering_the_secrets_of_the_Quintuplet_Cluster.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/9d/Ngc2363-V1Location.png/280px-Ngc2363-V1Location.png</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/d7/M33-013406.63_Pan-STARRS.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fc/Eta_Carinae.jpg/280px-Eta_Carinae.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/df/LBV_G0.120-0.048.jpg/280px-LBV_G0.120-0.048.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/c1/ESO_-_Eso1030a_%28by%29.jpg/300px-ESO_-_Eso1030a_%28by%29.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/5e/Arches_Cluster_hubble_friday_05292015.jpg/220px-Arches_Cluster_hubble_friday_05292015.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/7c/V1429AqlLightCurve.png/250px-V1429AqlLightCurve.png</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f2/The_young_cluster_R136.jpg/250px-The_young_cluster_R136.jpg</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>